■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
喜馬拉雅山脈  印度/巴基斯坦邊境
■
翻譯：No.Zero  七個柚子醬  持久君  Silence
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥  sienna  章魚埃克斯
翻譯：CS小明漫畫家  木淺薰  貝貝
時間軸：Kallen  貝貝  密斯恩
校對：早先森  sienna  紫玉
后期：賣萌芯片8T     總監：紫玉
孟買恐怖襲擊已經過去五年了
Five years since the terrorist attacks in Mumbai,
還有很多未知...
and there are still many un...
爆炸摧毀了一邊的...
The bomb struck one end of the...
慘狀殘酷地提醒著人們11月26日
A grim reminder of what happened at the Taj
泰姬陵所發生的事
on November 26th.
大火  可以看到所有的窗戶都...
Fire. You can see all the windows...
火光沖天
Fire gushing out.
泰姬陵二層搜救仍在進行
Still searching the second floor of the Taj.
阿米莉亞  你在哪
Amelia, where are you?
恐怖分子冷血射殺無辜群眾
Shot people needlessly in cold blood.
12次連環襲擊
The 12 coordinated attacks
害死了來自十個國家共166人
killed 166 victims from 10 countries.
我就揉了揉眼睛
I'm just rubbing my eyes here.
幾分鐘內  整座建筑都起了火
In just a few minutes, this whole building has caught fire.
死亡人數已達十個
10 dead!
中情局特工阿米莉亞·海斯是孟買襲擊的共犯
阿米莉亞·海斯
通緝
爸媽  我們想你們
Hey, Mom. Hey, Dad. We miss you.
她是我的了  爸爸
She's mine now, Dad.
你怎么能這樣做
How could you?
能解釋一下你為什么擅入
Can you explain why you were trespassing
本國政府轄區嗎
on government property?
晚上六點  我們在高防軍事地球同步衛星上
At 18:00 hours, we were alerted to a level-one sigint breach
發現了一個一級通信情報缺口
on a highly-protected military geosync satellite.
追蹤信號找到了你
We sourced the signal to you,
卻沒在你身上發現任何通訊設備
yet we found no communication equipment on your person,
更別提你是如何突破
let alone something with the processing power
日光反射加密防火墻的了
to break through a helio-encrypted firewall.
你能解釋一下嗎
Can you explain that?
她不喜歡你對她這么關注
You know, she doesn't like the attention you give her.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
給你送咖啡的女人
That woman who brought you coffee.
她結婚了  你的騷擾讓她感到不舒服
She's married, and you make her uncomfortable.
事實上  她很怕你
In fact, she's afraid of you.
為什么呢  巴德里
Why is that, Badri?
我沒告訴過你我的名字
I haven't told you our names.
這是你干的嗎
Did you just do that?
《智能緝兇》
第一季 第一集
馬里蘭州  切薩皮克灣
阿伯特  我81年還在宇航局時
Albert, when I was at NASA in '81,
我們把航天飛機送入了軌道
we sent the space shuttle into orbit.
現在一臺手機的處理能力就是當年
A cellphone today has a thousand times more processing power
一架航天飛機的千倍
than we put in that spacecraft.
科技不是革命
Technology is not revolutionary.
而是進化了
It's evolutionary.
這話真睿智
Ah, that's pretty good.
我喜歡
I like that.
我們家小浣熊回來了
Oh, boy. Looks like our raccoons are back.
好了  你回里屋去吧
All right, I think I'll keep you inside.
保險箱  一起帶走
這里的東西你隨便拿
Please, take whatever you want.
美國網戰司令部
弗吉尼亞州  天使崖
請出示證件
Identification, please.
皮特  我不為蘭利[中情局]做事
Pete, I don't work for Langley.
你要我派人去查這種情報
You want me to move assets on that kind of intel,
命令必須由上頭直接下達
it'll have to come directly from 1600.
-尼爾特工來了  -謝謝大家  沒其他事了
- Agent Neal's here. - Thank you, everyone. That'll be all.
萊利  我是莉莉安·斯特蘭德
Riley. Lillian Strand.
斯特蘭德女士  幸會
Ms. Strand. Pleasure to meet you.
我們見過一次  對吧
We met once before, didn't we?
是的  在空軍一號上  沒想到您還記得
Yes. On Air Force One. I didn't think you'd remember.
萊利  過去幾個月你一直在為一項
Riley, you have been vetted for months
你既沒有申請  也不知情的工作
for a job you neither applied for,
接受審核
nor are even aware of.
我們將候選人名單縮小到六人
We narrowed the list of candidates to six.
最后  我只請你來到這里
And in the end, you're the only one I brought here.
長官  我深感榮幸  但是我已經有工作了
Ma'am, I'm flattered, but I already have a job.
邊走邊說
Take a walk with me.
你對網戰司令部有何認識
What do you know about Cybercom?
該部門負責暗網搶救
You're responsible for deepnet salvage,
密碼分析  網路防御  數據挖掘
cryptanalysis, cyber defense, data mining...
還有一個叫"發條計劃"的項目
And a program called "Clockwork."
1939年  納粹開始研制一款終極核武器
In 1939, the Nazis began developing a doomsday weapon.
美國當局史無前例地動員所有資源來防御
The U.S. response was an unprecedented mobilization
史稱曼哈頓計劃
of resources called the Manhattan Project,
曼哈頓計劃  第二次世界大戰期間美國陸軍自1942年起開發核武器計劃的代號
導致大型殺傷性武器被研制出來
Resulting in the most devastating weapon ever built.
現在我們面臨著更為嚴峻的新威脅
Now we face new and even more insidious threats.
發條計劃就是現在的曼哈頓計劃
Clockwork is this generation's Manhattan Project.
已經積極推進了六個月
It's been active for six months
目前成功率百分之百
and has enjoyed a 100% success rate,
包括成功阻止了
included in that success
超級杯賽的爆炸案
is the thwarting of the Super Bowl bomber.
超級杯賽  1967年以來每年一度的美式橄欖球賽
我還以為是中情局解決的
I thought that was C.I.A.?
你到現在都還沒搞清楚
You haven't been cleared to think anything different...
這其中的區別
until now.
去年  "60分鐘"節目播報了一個四肢癱瘓的人
Last year, "60 minutes" aired a story about a quadriplegic
60分鐘  為美國的一個新聞雜志節目
她可以用思維操控她的機械臂
who could operate a robotic arm with her mind.
這要歸功于我們部門
The microchip that made that possible
研發出來的微芯片
was created right here.
當其他部門忙于
While other agencies have been busy
制造超越人類的人工智能時
trying to make artificial intelligence more human,
我們則賦予人類
we gave a human the kind of power
目前只有機器才能實現的能力
that had previously only been found in a machine.
我們創造出有史以來第一個
We created a man who's the first of his kind --
高級智能特工
an advanced intelligence agent.
快完了
We're almost done.
目前沒發現任何殘留病毒
We haven't found any residual virus.
什么病毒
What kind of virus?
震網病毒
Stuxnet --
世界上首個網絡超級武器
the world's first weaponized cyber worm.
-是電腦病毒嗎  -完全正確
- The computer virus? - Boo-yah.
唯一將它植入喜馬拉雅山脈中部
Of course, the only way to plant it in an isolated,
那個秘密基地的辦法
bunkerized system in the middle of the Himalayas
就是由加布里爾親身攜帶進入
was for Gabriel to carry it in himself,
我們正在確保沒有任何代碼藏進他的系統
which is why we're making sure none of the code burrowed in.
藏進什么  他是被麻醉了嗎
Burrowed into what? Is he under anesthesia?
我倒希望如此
I wish.
加布里爾  檢查完了
Gabriel, you're done.
終于完了
Finally.
萊利  你頭發換顏色了
Riley, you've changed your hair color.
我沒見過你吧
I don't believe we've met.
你給大學男友的郵件里帶著照片
Wow, that photo you e-mailed your boyfriend in college --
傳出來的東西得多加小心
got to be careful what you send out there in the world.
這被稱為數字化表現  對吧  亞摩斯
It's called digital permanence. Right, Amos?
不要擔心  他不能打印出來
Don't worry, he can't print.
再者  亞摩斯·彭布羅克  加布里爾的主技員
By the way, I'm Amos Pembroke, Gabriel's pri-tech.
主要技術人員
Primary technician.
這的人都喜歡使用簡稱
Nobody around here uses more syllables than they have to.
正好適合你
You'll fit right in.
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
-高考才1060分  -不是吧
- 1060 on your S.A.T.s? -Come on.
我不適合考試
I was a bad test taker.
美國特勤局特工  萊利·尼爾
你以為你是誰阿
And who the hell do you think you are?
密封記錄——僅政府可用
少年記錄是密封的  里面是什么呢
Whoa, a sealed juvenile record. What's that about?
-加布里爾  適可而止  -好
- Gabriel, don't open that file. - Fine.
是什么記錄  入店行竊
What's in it? Shoplifting?
跟我講講  外科醫生和化學家的女兒
Tell me, how's the daughter of a surgeon
怎么成一名特工的
and chemist become a Secret Service Agent?
總統特派小隊中最年輕的女性
Youngest woman ever appointed to presidential detail --
那可是傳奇職業生涯的開始
Now, that's the beginning of a storied career.
但現在又如何
But now what?
被一個大腦裝著芯片的
Following around a charming devil
男神耍得團團轉
with a microchip in his brain?
令人印象深刻啊  幾乎每句話都無比正確
Impressive. Almost every word of that was accurate.
幾乎  哪句錯了
Almost? Which word I get wrong?
"男神"
"Charming."
無論工作是什么
Whatever the job is,
我想你該另尋他人了
I think you should find someone else.
拜
Bye.
想得美
Nice try.
你別想嚇跑這個
But you're not gonna scare this one off.
萊利
Riley.
這就是你說的超級智能特工嗎
That guy is your advanced intelligence agent?
他曾是三角洲部隊的一級戰備作戰部隊成員
That guy was Delta Force, tier one.
五次前往伊拉克及阿富汗戰區
Five tours in Iraq and Afghanistan.
他是位英雄
He's a hero.
同時也行事魯莽  變化無常  性格叛逆
He's also reckless, unpredictable, and insubordinate.
即便如此你們還是給他植入了芯片
And you put a computer in his head.
我們將人腦直接與信息網絡連接
We connected a human being directly to the information grid --
包括互聯網  無線網  電話  衛星
Internet, Wi-Fi, telephone, satellite.
我是總統特勤局特工
I'm a secret service agent.
我來這兒能做什么
What could you possibly want me for?
這是我國至今所研發出的
This is the most valuable piece of technology
最具價值的科技產品
this country has ever created.
我要你替我們保護它
I want you to protect it for us.
你開玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
你覺得保護總統比這更重要嗎
You think protecting the president is more important than this?
恕我直言  長官
Respectfully, ma'am,
的確更重要
it is more important.
有趣  他可不這么認為
Funny. He didn't think so.
上一任做不好
Didn't work with the last one.
現在也一樣  我不需要保姆
It won't work now. I don't need a babysitter.
是嗎  那你的喜馬拉雅山脈之旅呢
No? What about your Himalayan adventure?
我派你去是為了植入病毒
I sent you there to plant a virus,
不是搜尋阿米莉亞
not to look for Amelia.
雖然確實很令人痛苦
As painful as it is to say,
你的妻子參與了一起她本該阻止的襲擊
your wife took part in an attack she was sent to prevent,
而她也在行動中喪命
and she died in the same attack.
印度國防情報局的報告中沒有提及她的死
The Indian D.I.A. files make no mention of her death.
但他們確實把她歸到了襲擊者中
But they did identify her as one of the attackers.
這也不代表她叛變了
That doesn't mean she turned.
中情局派她當了兩年臥底
The C.I.A. had her deep black for two years.
據我們所知  她還沒有暴露身份
For all we know, she's still dark.
孟買的那場大火里
A lot of bodies were incinerated
很多尸體都被燒為灰燼
in that fire in Mumbai,
從那以后她再沒有上報情況
And she never reported in
或在網絡中出現
or showed up on the grid again.
這就是你的證據嗎
And that's your evidence?
如果我晚上睡覺前  地面上沒有雪
If I go to bed at night and there's no snow on the ground
早上起來我在鏟雪  就代表下過雪了
and in the morning I'm shoveling, it snowed.
很好
Great.
加布里爾  已經五年了
Gabriel, it's been five years.
我不會放任你濫用機構資源
I'm not gonna let you bang and burn your own agency
就為了你無謂的堅持
in pursuit of this fairy tale that you're clinging to.
無論阿米莉亞遭遇了什么  她已經死了
Whatever became of Amelia, she's gone.
我很遺憾  但是時候向前看了
I'm sorry, but it's time to move on.
向前看
Move on?
你這輩子關心過任何人嗎  莉莉安
You ever cared for anyone in your life, Lillian?
說話小心點
Careful.
所以那女孩是派來管束我的嗎
So, that girl's supposed to keep me in line, huh?
可別小看"那女孩"
Let me tell you something about that girl.
去年她在一間休息室里被襲擊
She was attacked in a restroom last year
當時她在保護總統的孩子們
while protecting the President's children.
被多次刺傷
Stabbed multiple times.
仍重傷了四名襲擊者
She incapacitated all four men
并在晚飯前成功把女孩們帶回家了
and still managed to get those girls home for dinner.
請說
Yes?
國家情報局的副局長到了
The Deputy Director of National Intelligence is here.
有預約嗎
Is this on the calendar?
沒有  長官
No, ma'am.
讓他進來吧
Well, send him in.
莉莉安
Lillian.
卡爾
Carl.
抱歉突然來訪
Sorry for the surprise.
我知道我們一般不親自碰面
I know we don't usually do this in person,
但這回情況特殊
but this one's special.
-什么情況  -綁架  重要人物
- What do we have? - Kidnapping -- high value.
是你的手下  希恩·卡西迪博士
And he's one of yours. Dr. Shen Cassidy.
全體注意
Eyes up front.
現在有一樁綁架案
What you are about to see is a kidnapping.
被劫持者屬于紅色優先級
Victim is priority red.
視頻中很難認出
It's hard to make him out in the video,
但已經知道那是希尼多·卡西迪博士
but that's Dr. Shenendoah Cassidy.
如你們所知 卡西迪博士在今年退休前
As most of you know, until his retirement this year,
不僅是我們的頂級神經科學家
Dr. Cassidy was not only our top neuroscientist,
更是發條計劃的主要成員之一
he was the leading member of the clockwork team.
這個視頻是從哪兒來的
Where's this video from?
環境保護局的監視攝像拍到的
An E.P.A. camera-trap
本來用來監測切薩皮克微型蝙蝠的
intended to monitor the chesapeake dwarf bat.
-視頻已經銳化過了嗎  -正在處理
- Has it been scrubbed? - Working on it.
還沒能識別面部特征
No facial rec yet.
貨車的車牌號呢
What about the van's plates?
應該能恢復一部分
Looks like we may be able to dig out a partial.
亞摩斯  你跟他們一起去
Amos, I want you to go out there with them,
確保他的電腦安全
make sure his computers aren't compromised.
好  不過我完全不擔心
Will do, but I'm not concerned.
我給電腦加密了
I created the encryption protocol.
20-40位加密算法  堅不可破
20-40 bit. Impregnable.
除非他們用刑逼他說出密碼
Unless they torture him for the password.
如果他們進入了電腦
If they do gain access,
他們就會知道加布里爾的事
they could learn about Gabriel.
他可能已經成為目標了
He could be a target already.
好在有萊利保護我
Well, it's good thing we have Riley here to protect me.
聽著
Listen up.
這和我們以前處理的綁架案不同
This isn't like any kidnapping we've handled before.
以前時間有限但受威脅的只有被劫者
The clock always ticks on the victim.
而這次我們也同樣危險
This time, it ticks on us, too.
馬上開始工作
Get to work.
你那個密封檔案里是什么
So, what's in that sealed file of yours?
你居然沒看  真讓我驚訝
I'm surprised you didn't read it already.
你以為我是什么  動物嗎
What am I, an animal?
和毒品有關嗎
Was it drugs?
還是搶劫酒鋪了
You robbed a liquor store.
告訴我吧
Come on.
這種時候我們不是該互相分享增進感情嗎
I thought this was the part where we share and bond.
這種時候我只會越發
Seems like the part where I find out
感覺到你有多混蛋
how much of a pain in the ass you are.
怎么了
What is it?
綁匪是中國人
The kidnappers are Chinese.
你怎么可能知道這個
How could you possibly know that?
找到了
There you are.
卡西迪的口袋錄音筆
Cassidy's pocket recorder.
我走過來的路上發現的
I caught it when we walked up.
它有藍牙
Bluetooth.
我們家小浣熊回來了
Oh, Boy. Looks like our raccoons are back.
好了  你回里屋去吧
All right, I think I'll keep you inside.
保險箱  一起帶走
這就是那些中國人  翻譯一下
There's your Chinese. Translation?
把箱子帶走
"Bring the box."
帶走箱子
"Bring the box"?
你在哪學的中文
Where did you learn mandarin?
沒學過  我有翻譯軟件
I didn't. I got an app for that.
那你得更新了
You need an upgrade.
"Xiang"是"箱子"沒錯
"Xiang ze" means "Box", yes,
但"Baoxianxiang"的意思是"保險箱"
but "Bao shen xiang" means "Safe".
帶走保險箱
"Bring the safe."
加布里爾
Gabriel.
你能來太好了
I'm so glad you're here.
那我就放心了  我們一定可以找到他
Now I know we're gonna find him.
保險箱里有什么
What was in the safe?
我不知道  沒什么  只有爸爸的電腦
I don't know. Nothing. Just Dad's laptop.
電腦在保險箱里
The computer was in the safe?
是啊  他為了他的回憶錄  搞得草木皆兵
Yeah. He was real paranoid about his memoirs.
已經錄了幾個月了
He's been dictating them for months.
他說跟貓聊天都比這個容易
He said it was easier to talk to a cat,
所以我把錄音筆設成了聲控啟動
so I made the recorder voice-activated,
還能自動上傳到他的電腦里
even had it auto-upload to his laptop.
所以加布里爾才會收到它發出的信號
That's why it was sending out the signal Gabriel picked up.
-它在嘗試登陸電腦  -沒錯
- It was trying to log in. - Mm-hmm.
回憶錄里有不可外泄的秘密嗎
Is there anything compromising in those memoirs?
沒有
No.
不可能有  我們知道情報保密規定
No way. We know the rules about black intel.
而且我們離開網戰司令部后
Plus, you guys took back all the classified material
你們把所有加密材料都拿走了
when we left Cybercom.
我能問個問題嗎
Can I ask a question?
-不能  -我來問
- No. - I'll ask it.
如果電腦里沒有任何不可外泄的秘密
If there was nothing compromising on the computer
而且還被加密了  為什么還得放在保險箱里
And it was encrypted, why did it have to be in a safe?
要么電腦里還有別的東西
So, either there's something else on that computer...
要么保險箱里還有別的東西
or the computer's not the only thing in that safe.
要是知道你造了第二塊芯片的話
What would your government do to you
你的政府會怎么處置你
if they learned you made a second chip?
什么也不會做
Nothing.
因為它根本沒用
Because it doesn't work.
但愿你是騙我的  博士
I hope that's not true, doctor.
走
開燈
這間手術室
You will find this operating room
已經備齊了你會需要的一切工具
has been outfitted with everything you will need.
我會需要的一切工具
Everything I'll need?
我拿這些要做什么
Everything I'll need for what?
就算我想我也做不了
I couldn't do this even if I wanted to.
沒有眼鏡我什么也看不見
I cannot see without my glasses.
事實上
Actually...
我相信你動手術的時候是戴的這個
I believe you wear these for this operation.
你覺得我會把一個未測試過的  可能有缺陷的芯片
You think I'm going to implant an untested,
植入活體嗎
possibly defective chip in a live human?
不
No.
我  我也不知道為什么我撒了謊
Okay, I-I don't know why I lied.
我  我嚇壞了
Okay, I-I was -- I was scared.
加布里爾  我早應該告訴你的
Gabriel, I should have told you.
他還造了一塊芯片  為什么
He made another chip? Why?
你真的覺得他會滿足于此嗎
Well, did you really think his brain would just stop working?
他一向追求完美  你知道的
He's always perfecting. You know that.
我們本來要交給網站的
Look, we were gonna give it to Cybercom.
尼爾森  跟我們說說那些中國人
Nelson, tell us about the Chinese.
-中國人  什么中國人  -帶走你父親的人
- Chinese? What Chinese? - The men who took your father.
什么
What?!
等等  什么
Wait...what...
你們覺得
You guys think I had
-我跟這事有關嗎  -交易談崩了
- something to do with this?! - Did the deal go bad?
不不不  不  伙計們  別這樣
No, no, no! No! Guys, come on!
你們在說什么呢  我絕對不會
What are you talking about?! I would never!
-亞摩斯  -只管告訴他們真相吧  兄弟
- Amos? - Just tell them the truth, bro.
伙計們
Guys.
湖那邊是我們的產業嗎
Do we have an asset across the lake?
西南林木線那兒
Southwest tree line.
這是中國M99狙擊槍的實時圖像
This is a live image from a Chinese M99 sniper Rifle.
正如你所看到的  你的兩個兒子
As you can see, both of your sons
今天早上都加入了我們
have joined us this morning --
你的親生兒子和你寶貴的匹諾曹
The biological one and your precious Pinocchio.
《木偶奇遇記》中  創造匹諾曹的木匠如兒子般看待匹諾曹
別擔心
Don't worry.
我不是什么惡人
I'm not a monster.
今天我只會殺一個
I will only kill one today.
不要  求你了
No, please.
我看到一些東西了
I'm getting something.
他們在傳輸信號
They're broadcasting a signal.
-狙擊手  -趴下
- Sniper! - Down!
求你了  你要我做什么都行
Please, I will do whatever you want.
但是你得明白這個為什么沒有用
But you have got to understand why this can't work.
我該怎么解釋呢
How do I explain this?
我們通過欺騙神經遞質來創造一種第六感
We are coaxing neurotransmitters to create a sixth sense.
要做到這樣  我們發現試驗者
To do that, we discovered the candidate had to possess
必須要擁有一種極其罕見的突變基因
an extremely rare genetic mutation.
叫做雅典-4U7R
It's called Athens-4U7R.
你懂嗎
Do you understand?
加布里爾就有
Gabriel was a gift.
進來
這是陳美
This is Mei Chen.
她有那種突變基因  雅典-4U7R
She possesses the gene mutation, Athens-4U7R.
你這是在浪費時間
Look, you're wasting time.
我父親還不知道在外面哪里
My father's still out there somewhere.
你們都失去理智了嗎
Have you all lost your mind?!
從什么時候起  莉莉安接管審訊了
Since when does Lillian run an interrogation?
那芯片對國家安全至關重要
That chip is vital to national security.
因為這涉及私人問題
Since it got personal.
數據上并沒有明顯的線索證明他跟這有關
There's no digital signpost he's involved.
沒郵件  沒語音留言  什么都沒有
No e-mails, voicemails, nothing.
他管理他父親的實驗室  那也就是說
He runs his father's lab -- that means
他很清楚怎么避開這些陷阱  對吧
he knows exactly how to avoid those traps, right?
我喜歡這新來的女孩
I like the new girl.
她才不是新來的女孩
She's not the new girl.
樓下大廳有咖啡間
In fact, there's a coffee room down the hall.
我在這很安全  他們都是熟人
I'm pretty sure I'm safe here. These are my people.
尼爾森不也是你的熟人嗎
Wasn't Nelson one of your people?
他本來想交給你
He was gonna give it to you.
他要交給我們  就像那樣交嗎
He was just gonna hand it over to us, just like that?
左右逢源不是忠誠
Well, loyalty doesn't always go both ways.
你覺得我不忠誠嗎
Oh, you think I was disloyal?
你本來可以留他在身邊的
You could have kept him on.
他做他的工作  你做你的  我們心存感激
He did his job, you did yours, and we are grateful for that.
但項目進入了調動階段
But the project entered the deployment phase.
他能提供更多
He had more to give.
現在新的芯片還沒測試過
Now, the new chip hasn't been tested,
但是摩爾定律決定  它必定
but Moore's Law dictates it will be significantly
比原型更快更強
faster and more robust than the original.
而你居然把它交給了外國政府
And you've just given that to a foreign government.
我干嘛要讓自己的父親置身危險中
Why would I put my own father in danger?!
-為了報復他  -為了報復他什么
- To get back at him. - For what?
為了加布里爾
For Gabriel.
誰又能怪你呢
Who could blame you?
你爸爸偏愛他
The way your father doted over him
就好像加布里爾是自己的親生兒子
as if Gabriel were his own son.
這太荒唐了
This is insane.
我們擦拭了錄像  得到一部分車牌號碼
We scrubbed the video, and we got a partial plate.
馬里蘭州H-b
Maryland -- "H-b."
但跟數據庫所有的白色面包車都不匹配
Doesn't match any white vans in the database, though.
也許車牌是從其他車輛盜取的
What if the plates were lifted from another car?
我進入國家機動車數據庫了
I'm in the D.M.V. database now.
馬里蘭州車輛管理
一輛藍色88年版雪佛蘭卡布萊斯
A blue '88 chevy caprice
曾停在卡斯特路2300街區
parked on the 2300 block of Castor road
報失過開頭為"H-b"的車牌
reported stolen plates that begin with "H-b."
真是好把戲
That is a great party trick.
那輛卡普萊斯半徑48公里之內
How many white chevy vans
-有多少輛白色雪佛蘭  -27輛
- are in a 30-mile radius of that caprice? - 27.
我們要找到的是98年版雪佛蘭阿斯特羅
Ours is a '98 chevy astro.
那么范圍縮小到兩輛車了
That narrows it to two vans.
雪佛蘭  阿斯托羅面包車
一輛因為六周前未交停車費而被拖走
One was towed for unpaid parking tickets six weeks ago
現在還停在保管場
and still sits in the impound lot.
另一輛是注冊商務使用
The other is registered to a business
注冊公司名叫"靶心彩彈"
called "Bullseye Paintball."
錄像顯示  車子的一側
The video revealed paint splatters
有彩彈飛濺的痕跡
on one side of the van.
猜猜"靶心彩彈"在哪
Guess where Bullseye Paintball is?
唐人街
Chinatown.
這地方真大
This place is huge.
是啊  我們正在接收衛星信息
Yeah. We're getting a satellite feed.
紅外線可以反映人數
Infrared will get us a head count
和任何他們有可能藏身的地下室
and any basement where they might be hiding him.
衛星多久可以到位
How long till the satellite's in position?
亞摩斯說十五分鐘
Amos says 15 minutes.
先四處看看吧
Let's take a look around.
我們應該等待突擊小組
We should wait for the tac team.
你從沒當過俘虜嗎
You've ever been held captive?
十五分鐘有可能感覺像一輩子那么長
15 minutes can seem like a lifetime.
說吧
Say it.
你是對的
You were right.
你的密封檔案
Auto theft?
是汽車盜竊嗎
Your sealed file.
是卡西迪的東西
Those are Cassidy's.
你們闖入私人領地了
Hey! You're trespassing!
王福  通緝
你好啊王福
Hello, huang fu.
聯邦特工  舉起手來
Federal agents! Hands in the air!
殺死他們
他們有槍
Gun!
你為我中槍了  你搞什么飛機
You took a bullet for me? What the hell are you doing?
這是我的工作
My job.
加布里爾  回話
Gabriel, talk to me.
萊利中彈了  重復  萊利中彈了
Riley's been hit! Repeat, Riley's been hit!
突擊小組五分鐘后趕到
Tac team is five minutes out.
剛左和詹姆森正在確定你們的位置
Gonzo and Jameson are trying to reach your location.
沒時間了  我們得轉移
No time. Can't stay here.
都出去  現在
Everybody out, now!
快走
Go, go, go! Go!
我到那邊去
我需要衛星信號
I need that satellite!
亞摩斯  衛星干什么呢
Amos, where's that bird?
在太空移動一個五頓重的大家伙
Moving five tons of metal through space
又不像訂塊披薩那么簡單
isn't like ordering a pizza.
快弄好  亞摩斯
Now would be good, Amos.
加布里爾  衛星就位倒數  五  四
Gabriel, satellite in five, four,
三  二
three, two...
三角定位中
衛星鎖定
衛星紅外圖像啟動
I've got satellite infrared.
干掉他
快走
Let's go!
殺掉他
有錢嗎
Got any cash on you?
傳說不回報救你性命的人
The romans said it's bad luck not to give something
會招致厄運
to the person that saved your life.
聽說過
I've heard that.
20塊應該能抵掉厄運
I think a 20 should about cover it.
我該給你嗎  是我救了你吧
You think I'm paying you? I saved your life.
受傷的是我吧
I'm bleeding.
只是小傷而已  別小題大做
It's just a flesh wound. Don't be dramatic.
沒找到卡西迪  他不在
Hey, no sign of Cassidy. He's not here.
你知道那個小丑的表弟是誰嗎
You'll never guess who that clown's cousin is.
金康鎮
Jin Cong.
不會吧
Are you serious?
金康鎮又是誰
Who the hell is Jin Cong?
中國智能人
Chinese intelligence.
怎么會失敗
Why hasn't this worked?
她怎么還在昏迷  博士
Why is she not awake, doctor?
我警告過你可能會如此
I warned you that this could happen.
她可能會昏迷幾周  幾個月  甚至不會醒來
This poor girl could wake up in weeks, months, or never.
我們在做的
We're meddling with things
是我們還不完全了解的事
that we're only beginning to understand.
見過中式M99號狙擊來復槍嗎
Have you ever seen a chinese M99 sniper Rifle?
這是世界上最精良的武器
This is the finest-made weapon in the world --
精準的瞄準系統
pinpoint accuracy.
你想干什么
What are you planning on doing with that thing?
你在耍花樣嗎  博士
Did you sabotage us, doctor?
沒有
No!
我說過  她有蘇醒的可能
Like I said, she could still wake up.
你得有點耐心
You need to give her more time.
你得給我換成那個能用的芯片
You will replace this chip with the one that works.
你沒有那芯片
You don't have that chip.
馬上就會有
I will shortly.
為什么讓我呆在藏身所里
What am I doing in a safe house?
-我讓你退出  -什么
- I'm pulling you out. - You're what?!
才剛一天
In the last 24 hours,
你就差點死了兩次
you almost got yourself killed twice.
我在執行任務
That's the job.
F-35  史上最貴的戰斗機
The F-35's the most expensive airplane ever built.
還不是剛造好就上戰場了
The first thing they did was throw it in a war zone.
我腦袋里這東西是很貴重
This thing in my head may be valuable,
但也不能因此就束之高閣吧
but you don't want it sitting in a hangar.
那也不能
I also don't want it
讓它為點雞毛蒜皮就犧牲
getting lost in some dangle up gone wrong.
好感動
Touching.
你知道如果這芯片落到別人手里
Do you have any idea what would happen
會有什么后果
if this chip ends up in the wrong hands?
今天是中國  明天可能是俄羅斯
Today, China -- tomorrow, the Russians.
-還有韓國  伊朗  -我知道利害關系
- Korea, Iran -- - I know the stakes.
-所以你才得少惹麻煩  -我已經有麻煩了
- Then why can't you stay unproblem? - I am on-problem!
你就不該在
You had no business going
突擊隊到之前行動
into that place before the tac team arrived.
私事上  你就更沒權利
When it's personal, you think it gives you the license --
這不僅關乎我個人
This is more than personal.
卡西迪如同我父親一般  阿米莉亞是我的妻子
Cassidy's like a father to me, and Amelia's my wife.
所以我才說是私事
You just made my point.
聽著
Look...
你找到了金康鎮
You got us to Jin Cong.
下面的事由我接手
I'll take it from here.
好吧
All right.
感覺如何
How are you feeling?
加布里爾的妻子究竟怎么了
What's the real on Gabriel's wife?
你說什么
Excuse me?
你希望我保護他
You want me to take bullets for him,
那我得知道他會在哪出問題
then I need to know where he's gonna be unpredictable.
事實是阿米莉亞·海斯
The real is that Amelia Hayes
是美國的敵人
was an enemy of the United States.
她在印度軍隊做臥底  后來轉投敵方
She was deep cover with the Lashkar, and she turned.
就這樣
End of story.
如果這是真的
If that's true,
你為什么要違反所有規定
Why would you violate all established protocol
將世界上最強大的智能武器
by entrusting the man who loves her
委派給深愛她的男人
with the most powerful intelligence weapon on earth?
你不相信她是叛徒  對嗎
You don't believe she was a traitor, do you?
你應該也不信她已經死了
I bet you don't even believe she's dead.
讓我把話說清楚
Let me be very clear with you.
我們花費數十億美元  制造出任何國家
We've spent billions of dollars creating something
不惜發動戰爭奪取的東西
that every nation on earth would go to war to possess.
你不是來質疑我的
You're not here to question me.
你是來保護它的
You're here to keep it safe.
他  不是它
Him. Not it.
他是活生生的人  她是他的妻子
He's a human being. She's his wife.
他不會讓這事就這么算了
He's not gonna let this go,
也不該這樣
nor should he.
加布里爾
Gabriel...
你在干什么
what are you doing?
你的肩膀怎么樣了
How's your shoulder?
你打算告訴我你在做什么嗎
Are you gonna tell me what's going on?
我正在進行網絡渲染
I'm cyber-rendering.
這是芯片能做到的意料之外的事
It's something the chip does that nobody expected.
我能在腦中重現事發時的虛擬場景
I can create a virtual snapshot of an event in my mind
并穿行其中
and then walk through it.
不止這樣
But it's more than that.
這就像虛擬的證據墻一樣
It's... it's like a virtual evidence wall.
你正在這樣做嗎
You're doing this right now?
我所能獲取的信息  都能直接用眼睛看到
All the intel I have access to, I can see it.
芯片像電腦一樣處理信息
The chip processes it like a computer,
而大腦將信息進行分析消化
but my brain metabolizes it like...
和普通人沒什么兩樣
well, like a brain.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
卡西迪凝視著貨車
Cassidy's staring into the van.
然后呢
And?
他臉上表情有些問題
There's something about his face.
不是恐懼  而是...
It's not fear. It's...
舊識
recognition.
你說你只能獲取存在的信息
You said you could only access available intel.
在監控錄像中  我們看不清卡西迪
We couldn't really see Cassidy in the surveillance video,
你怎么能看清他的臉呢
so how are you seeing his face?
記住  渲染畫面是由我自己創造的
Well, remember, the render is generated by me-
半虛半實
part fact, part imagination.
所以是你推斷出來的
So you're extrapolating?
我把它當做夢境  在夢中進行分析
I think of it like a dream, analyze it like a dream.
潛意識告訴我
My subconscious wants to tell me that...
卡西迪認識綁匪
Cassidy knew his kidnapper.
是尼爾森  其他人不知道卡西迪在研究什么
Nelson. No one else knew what Cassidy was working on.
我原以為是這樣
That's what I thought, but...
但是芯片的設計圖在卡西迪的電腦里
the plans for that chip were on Cassidy's computer,
尼爾森不是唯一可接觸到電腦的人
and Nelson's not the only one that had access to it.
亞摩斯編寫的密碼
Amos wrote the encryption code.
20-40比特  無法破解
20-40 bit. Impregnable.
穿好衣服  我們要走了
Get your gear. We're leaving.
伙計們
Hey, guys.
我來看看萊利怎么樣了
I wanted to see how Riley was doing.
王八蛋  我要抓你回去
Son of a bitch, I'm taking you in.
你抓不了我  加布里爾
You're not taking me anywhere, Gabriel.
我是來抓你的
I'm the one taking you.
華盛頓特區  巖溪公園
我有一段安全屋的監控錄像
I have a surveillance video from one of our safe houses
里面顯示我方兩名特工
that shows two of our assets
被一群中國持槍者劫持
Being taken by Chinese gunmen.
我聽說你們也有一個人身涉其中
I hear, too, one of your own was involved.
這世上真正的秘密已經不多了  莉莉安
There are very few secrets left, Lillian.
你我都得習慣這一點
We must get used to that.
此次事件和我方無關
We were not involved in this incident.
而我們查到了你們的一個特工頭上
We've sourced this to one of your operatives --
金康鎮
Jin Cong.
金康鎮是個叛徒
Jin Cong is a traitor.
你指望我會相信這個金康鎮
You expect me to believe that Jin Cong,
作為你們的高級特工
one of your highest-ranking officers,
已經叛變了
has been disavowed?
金康鎮無法接受我國的改革理念
Jin Cong rejects the reforms in my country.
他希望我們回到過去
He would take us back to a time
回到一個你我都無暇欣賞此等美景的時代
when you and I could not enjoy such a pleasant view.
我覺得你知道康鎮在哪
I think you know where Cong is.
我父親曾告訴我這行里
My father once told me that there are
有三種硬通貨可以用來交易
three types of currency in this business.
一種是機密
You can trade in secrets,
一種是謊言
you can trade in lies,
還有一種是人情
or you can trade in favors.
我為什么要賣你這個人情
And why would I do such a favor?
因為這是筆好生意
Because it's good business.
你知道我和亞摩斯在一起呆了多久嗎
Do you know how many hours I've spent with Amos...
一起泡在實驗室里  做各種測試
...sitting in that lab, all those tests,
各種升級  各種診斷
software updates, diagnostics?
和別人如此親近  本以為了解他了
You get pretty close to someone, think you know him.
你最好讓我看一下
I better take a look at that.
只是看看傷口  不用臉紅心跳
Just the wound -- don't get excited.
傷口沒有開線  但看起來還是有點不妙
Well, the stitches are holding, but it doesn't look great.
過失殺人
Manslaughter.
沒定我的罪  但所有人都同意封存檔案
I wasn't convicted, but everyone agreed to seal the file.
想說服他們并不難
It wasn't hard to convince them.
我10歲時父母離了婚
My parents split when I was 10.
而我媽媽
My mother...
很快就開始另尋新歡
started dating a new guy soon after.
但她眼光顯然不太好
She wasn't very discriminating.
接下來的五年
And for the next five years, uh...
我沒能做什么保護我們母女免受傷害
I didn't do anything to protect us from him.
終于有一天  我...  我出手了
Then one day, I...I did.
從此你就走上了安保這條路
And you've been protecting people ever since.
你知道他們雇我來不光是為了保護你
You know I wasn't just hired to protect you.
我當然知道
Yeah, I know.
他們是想讓你阻止我尋找阿米莉亞
You're supposed to keep me from looking for Amelia.
沒錯
Yeah.
管他們怎么想
Well, hell with that.
你們要把他帶到哪里去
Where are you taking him?
你們要帶他到哪里去
Where are you taking him?!
加布里爾
Gabriel.
我的孩子  他們告訴我你死了
Oh, my boy, they told me you were dead.
我也很高興你活得好好的  博士
Glad to see you're still ticking, too, Doc.
博士  現在你知道該干什么了吧
Doctor, you know what you must do now.
你要是敢拒絕  我就自己動手
Refuse, and I will dig the chip
把芯片從他腦袋里挖出來
Out of his dead skull myself.
你管這叫無菌室
You call this a sterile field?
把他捆起來
我看他們一點都不擔心感染
I don't think they're worried about infection.
輕點
All right, be careful.
用不著弄傷他
You don't have to hurt him.
我會給你一些咪達唑侖[安定劑]
I'm gonna be giving you some midazolam.
它能讓你在麻醉前放松下來
It will relax you before the anesthesia.
我很抱歉  加布  我
I'm so sorry, Gabe. I --
我沒別的選擇
I don't see another option.
你給他用的什么
What did you give him?
我不明白
-怎么回事  -心源性休克
- What's happening?! - He's in cardiogenic shock!
加布  加布你聽得到嗎
Gabe?! Gabe, can you hear me?
過來  壓住他  快壓住他
Here, hold him down. Hold him down!
怎么回事  快告訴我怎么回事
What's happening? I demand to know what is happening.
我不知道  我不知道這白癡用的什么藥
I don't know. I don't know what this idiot gave him!
進來幫我
給我納洛酮
I need naloxone!
納洛酮  快去給我拿納洛酮
Naloxone! Get me naloxone! Go!
你沒事吧  博士
You all right, Doc?
我們離開這里吧
Let's get the hell out of here.
我給你拿了杯水
I brought you some water.
沒興趣
Not interested.
因為我他們才沒殺了你
Look, I'm the only reason they haven't killed you yet.
你知道康鎮多有錢嗎
Do you have any idea how much money Cong has?
萊利  我們沒必要變成敵人
We don't have to be enemies, Riley.
我們可以做朋友
We could be friends.
晚安  亞摩斯
Good night, Amos.
這東西有用嗎
Would this help?
走吧
Come on.
加布里爾  你朋友在我手上
Gabriel, I have your friend.
我想做個交易
I'm willing to make a trade.
我想你很容易就能找到我們
I imagine you can find us quite easily.
找到他了
Got him.
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
我內心可比外表強大
I'm tougher than I look.
博士  對我來說  你很強大了
You look pretty tough to me, Doc,
但你哪也不用去
but you're not going anywhere.
-放下你的武器  -別這么做  加布里爾
- Drop your weapon. - Don't do it, Gabriel.
要結束這事只有兩種方法
There are only two ways this ends --
要么打爆她的頭  要么把你腦袋開了
Either I open her head, or I open yours.
-開槍  -放下武器  跟我走
- Shoot him! - Put the weapon down and come with me,
-我就放她走  -別這么做  加布里爾
- and I'll let her go. - Don't do it, Gabriel.
你欠我二十塊
You owe me 20 bucks.
我不想欠你二十塊
I don't want to owe you 20 bucks.
慢慢放下槍
Put the gun down slowly.
往左邊一點
A little to the left.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
放下槍
Do it now!
再左邊一點
Little more.
放下槍
Drop the gun!
往下低三度
Three degrees down.
開槍  博士
Now, Doc!
要不要和我解釋一下
Want to explain to me
為什么我們把金康鎮交回給中國政府
why we're giving Jin Cong back to the Chinese?
我們要做個交易
We're making a trade.
你說你手上有情報
You said you had information...
關于阿米莉亞·海斯的
about Amelia Hayes.
巴基斯坦方面聲稱她還活著
The Pakistanis claim she is alive.
她在哪
Where is she?
他們已經監視她
They had her under surveillance
長達三個月了
as recently as three months ago.
我要證據
I need proof.
六月十二號她從
She boarded a flight
旁遮普[印度城市]乘機前往蘇黎世
from Punjab to Zurich on June 12th.
我相信你自己能找到那個視頻
I'm sure you can find the video yourself.
我要去蘇黎世
I need to go to Zurich.
-不  你要去西雅圖  -西雅圖
- No. You need to go to Seattle. - Seattle?
八個碼頭工人輻射中毒
Eight dock workers are sick with radiation poisoning.
昨天海關在一個從馬來西亞來的
Customs found traces in a container
集裝箱里找到了線索
that arrived from Malaysia yesterday.
-莉莉安  -去西雅圖  加布里爾
- Lillian - Seattle, Gabriel.
處理完那事后
After that...
別告訴我你的旅行計劃對我倆都好
it's better for both of us if you don't tell me your travel plans.
我只是想說謝謝
I just wanted to say thank you.
為了什么  這件事從未發生過
For what? This never happened.
你還好吧
You okay?
還好
Yeah.
我是不會改變的
I ain't gonna change, you know.
如果他們要機器人  可以自己造一個
If they wanted a robot, they could have built one.
如果想要的一個人類  他們也有了
They wanted a human, and they got one.
二十塊  給我干嘛
$20 -- what's this for?
留給下次的
For the next time.